Hi, I'm Zhilin, the founder of Kimi. Six
안녕하세요, 저는 Kimi의 창립자 즈힐린입니다. 여섯
months ago, we released Kimi K2. It was
개월 전, 저희는 Kimi K2를 출시했습니다. 그것은
the first open model to scale pertaining to
오픈 모델로서는 최초로
one trillion parameters. Later, we introduced Kimi K2
1조 개 파라미터까지 확장된 모델이었습니다. 이후 Kimi K2
Thinking. It scaled the thinking time of agents
Thinking을 소개했습니다. 이는 에이전트의 사고 시간을
for solving long horizon tasks. It performed interleaved
장기 과제를 해결하도록 확장했습니다. 또한
thinking with tool calling for up to 300
도구 호출과 번갈아 생각하는 과정을 최대 300
steps, all on its own. Today, we're dropping
단계까지 스스로 수행했습니다. 오늘 저희는
our latest model, Kimi K2.5. K2.5
최신 모델 Kimi K2.5를 공개합니다. K2.5는
is a powerful model that
강력한 모델로
excels at agents, coding, vision, and general capabilities,
에이전트, 코딩, 비전, 그리고 전반적인 역량에서 뛰어나며,
and it is open source. K2.5 sets
오픈 소스입니다. K2.5는
new records on the most challenging agentic benchmarks,
가장 도전적인 에이전트 벤치마크에서 새로운 기록을 세웠고,
including Humanities Last Exam, Browse Comp, and Deep
Humanities Last Exam, Browse Comp, 그리고 Deep
Search QA. K2.5 is also a very
Search QA를 포함합니다. K2.5는 또한 매우
strong coding model. We didn't just want Kimi
강력한 코딩 모델입니다. 저희는 Kimi가
to code, we wanted it to have an
그저 코딩만 하길 원한 것이 아니라,
eye for design. It weaves designer-grade websites,
디자인 감각도 갖추길 바랐습니다. 디자이너급 웹사이트를 엮어 내고,
a flow with great
훌륭한 흐름을 가진
face, and visual poetry. K2.5 and visual
감각, 그리고 시각적 시를 만들어냅니다. K2.5와 시각적
poetry. K2.5 lowers the barrier of entry
시입니다. K2.5는 진입 장벽을 낮춥니다
with the vision capabilities. Simply upload a screen
비전 기능으로요. 화면
recording. Kimi K2.5 will rebuild it from
녹화를 업로드하기만 하면, Kimi K2.5가 이를
scratch with clean professional code. Going beyond front
깔끔하고 전문적인 코드로 처음부터 다시 구축합니다. 프런트
-end design, K2.5 is great at software
엔드 디자인을 넘어, K2.5는 소프트웨어
engineering. Kimi Code is our new coding product.
엔지니어링에도 뛰어납니다. Kimi Code는 저희의 새로운 코딩 제품입니다.
Kimi Code supports images and videos as inputs.
Kimi Code는 이미지와 비디오를 입력으로 지원합니다.
It also automatically discovers existing skills into your
또한 기존 스킬을 자동으로 찾아 여러분의
working
작업
environment in the environment in Kimi Code. Next,
환경, 즉 Kimi Code의 환경에 통합합니다. 다음은
Office. To make Kimi even more helpful in
오피스입니다. Kimi를 일상 워크플로에서 더 유용하게 만들기 위해
your daily workflow, K2.5 has mastered the
K2.5는
core skills of the Office Suite. Whether it
오피스 스위트의 핵심 스킬을 마스터했습니다.
is building a complex financial model, handling the
복잡한 재무 모델을 만들거나, 처리하는 것이든
formatting of a professional PDF, or crafting a
전문적인 PDF의 서식을 다루거나, 혹은
consulting-level deck, we want to give that
컨설팅 수준의 덱을 만들든, 저희는 그
power to everyone. Tasks that used to take
힘을 모두에게 주고 싶습니다. 예전에는
days, like merging 50 different department reports, or
50개의 서로 다른 부서 보고서를 합치는 것처럼 며칠이 걸리던 작업이나,
turning a 30,000
3만
work paper into a precise pitch deck, now
단어짜리 작업 문서를 정확한 피치 덱으로 바꾸는 일도 이제는
happen in 10 minutes. With K2.5, we
10분 만에 이루어집니다. K2.5로 저희는
go from one agent to an agent's room.
단일 에이전트에서 에이전트 룸으로 전환합니다.
Instead of asking one agent to do everything,
한 에이전트에게 모든 것을 시키는 대신,
K2.5 creates and coordinates each room of
K2.5가 각 룸을 만들고 조율하여
specialized agents to work in parallel.
전문화된 에이전트들이 병렬로 작업하게 합니다.
These specialized agents are essentially copies of K2
이러한 전문화된 에이전트들은 본질적으로 K2
.5, but with different roles and different subtasks.
.5의 복사본이지만, 서로 다른 역할과 서로 다른 하위 과제를 갖습니다.
Nothing is predefined. The roles and subtasks are
미리 정의된 것은 없습니다. 역할과 하위 과제는
created on the fly
즉석에서
by K2.5. Running in parallel substantially reduces
K2.5에 의해 생성됩니다. 병렬 실행은
the time needed for a complex task. For
복잡한 작업에 필요한 시간을 크게 줄입니다. 예를 들어
market research spanning 100 companies, it orchestrates a
100개 기업에 걸친 시장 조사에서는 이를 오케스트레이션해
swarm of analysts for 10 around in minutes,
10여 명 규모의 분석가 스웜을 몇 분 안에 구성하여,
not weeks. For complex translation projects of 300
몇 주가 아니라 몇 분 만에 해냅니다. 300
pages, it mobilizes a team of linguists for
페이지짜리 복잡한 번역 프로젝트에서는 언어학자 팀을 동원해
rapid, accurate delivery. For literature synthesis across 50
빠르고 정확하게 납품합니다. 50
papers, it fills 10 senior researchers to conduct
편의 논문 문헌 종합에서는 10명의 시니어 연구원을 투입해
parallel analysis and generate a comprehensive survey.
병렬 분석을 수행하고 포괄적인 서베이 보고서를 생성합니다.
Instantly. Training the agent swamps at scale is
즉시입니다. 대규모로 에이전트 스웜을 훈련하는 것은
technically challenging. We rebuild our reinforcement learning infrastructure
기술적으로 도전적입니다. 저희는 강화학습 인프라를 재구축하고
and optimize the training algorithms to ensure the
훈련 알고리즘을 최적화하여
best efficiency and performance.
최고의 효율과 성능을 보장합니다.
All of these capabilities come together in K2
이 모든 역량은 K2
.5, a powerful open source model. You can
.5라는 강력한 오픈 소스 모델에 결집됩니다. 여러분은
experience all of this starting today on K2
오늘부터 K2
.5 or the K2.5 app. For software
.5 또는 K2.5 앱에서 이를 모두 경험할 수 있습니다. 소프트웨어
engineers, we recommend pairing K2.5 with K2
엔지니어에게는 K2.5를 K2
.5.
.5와 함께 쓰는 것을 권장합니다.
And also K2.5 is available via our
또한 K2.5는 저희
API. Go play with it and tell us
API를 통해서도 이용할 수 있습니다. 사용해 보시고 의견을
what you think. Thanks.
어떻게 생각하시는지 들려주세요. 감사합니다.